# CHARLES BRANDON KILGORE

Atlanta, GA

Phone: 478-251-6961 Email: Brandonk1023@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/charles-kilgore-69695b135 GitHub: https://github.com/Brandonk1023

## **SUMMARY**

Passionate and solutions-driven web development graduate from Georgia Tech. Experience in tech support utilizing a combination of strong communication, collaboration, problem-solving, and analytical skills. Strong ability to learn, design, build, and maintain websites. I have experience working in a fast-paced and diverse team environment leading and collaborating to achieve team goals. I have strong interest in backend technologies, application security, cloud technology, and mobile technology.

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

<u>Frameworks/Tools</u>: jQuery, Node.js, Express.js, MySQL, GitHub, BootStrap, Handlebars, MongoDB, npm, Insomnia, VS Code, Heroku, Sequelize, REACT, Tailwind, DaisyUI, MaterialUI, ChakraUI

Software Languages: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SQL, Python

**Operating Systems: Windows, Debian Linux, Mac** 

# PROJECT EXAMPLES

FoodWillBeerUsApart: https://github.com/Brandonk1023/FoodWillBeerUsApart Deployed Project: https://stbuiemory.github.io/FoodWillBeerUsApart/

- An application that provides an easy to use tool for beer and food pairing. The user can also save their favorite beer and food pairings for quick reference.
- Researched API's and their implementation, assisted with JavaScript functionality
- Tech: ¡Query, Bulma, Punk API, Pexel API, JavaScript, HTML.

# Express-Note-Taker: https://github.com/Brandonk1023/Express-Note-Taker Deployed Project: https://rocky-harbor-14327.herokuapp.com/

- A simple application that a user can use to store, delete, and edit notes for reviewing later.
- created backend routes, connected the front end
- **Tech**:Express, Heroku, JavaScript, npm, node

#### QuackCraft3DPrinting: https://github.com/Brandonk1023/QUACKCRAFT-3D-PRINTING

- A 3D printing centric React application for users to get information on 3D printing.
- Managed project team, created routes, connected front-end, created components
- **Tech**:Express, Heroku, JavaScript, npm, node, React, MongoDB, Mongoose, MaterialUI, ChakraUI

## Pot It Like It's Hot: https://github.com/stbuiemory/2kPerDay

- An application that allows users to look at the care requirements of different types
  of plants and add them to their online collection. The users are then prompted
  when it is time to water their plants with reminders in their garden screen.
- Created backend routes, researching API and implementation, Implementation of Passport for authentication. Assisting with frontend JavaScript code as needed
- **Tech**:Passport, Express, npm, Heroku, Perennial API, Node, Handlebars, MySQL, Sequelize, JavaScript, node

#### EXPERIENCE

#### Cox Automotive 2022-CURRENT

### **Dealer Concierge II/Customer Care Specialist II**

- Provide tier one support for customer request
- Troubleshoot technology issues for products/solutions
- Provide training on products to dealers and sales
- Identify patterns to find possible product/technology defects
- Diagnose technology related issues
- Provided coaching on products to team members

## Farmers Insurance - Tettleton Agency 2020-2021

### **Customer Service Representative**

- Provided first contact support for customer requests
- Helped diagnose/resolve customer tech/support issues
- Helped educate/determine customer coverage needs
- Quoted new and current business
- Worked event booths to bring in potential customers

#### **Brandon Kilgore Photography 2013-CURRENT**

#### Freelance Photographer

- Provided photographic coverage for client events/portraits
- Worked on multiple personal documentary Projects
- Cataloged artwork/events for Georgia Southern Art Dept.
- 2017 Betty Foy Sanders Scholarship Winner

#### **KEH CAMERA INC 2020-2020**

#### Camera Technician

- Tested/graded/repaired photographic equipment
- Recorded issues/data for repair and grading purposes

#### **Triumph Aero-Structures 2019-2020**

#### Tooling/Procurement Planner 2019-2020 | Assembly 2013-2015

- Worked with vendors on pricing and lead-time improvements
- Assisted with rebuild of inventory system
- Responsible for cultivating vendor relationships
- Maintained inventory and planning of tools and materials
- Solved tooling issues with production to meet goals/deadlines
- Lead Tool-Crib Team to support productions needs
- Assisted with tool setup, troubleshoot, and repair
- Read and followed blueprint specs to assemble parts
- Worked on tight deadlines to finish parts for shipment

#### **Georgia Southern Shooting Sports Center 2015-2018**

#### Range Master 2016-2018 | Range Safety Officer 2015-2016

- Maintained operations, equipment, and safety of the range
- Created/collaborated on documents used for range operation
- Managed team to accomplish goals and operations of facility
- Responsible for coaching classes and running tournaments
- Screened individuals seeking membership

# **EDUCATION**

Full Stack Flex Coding Bootcamp: Georgia Tech, Atlanta, GA 2023

- A fast paced, intense 24 week program on fullstack web development.
- Provided experience live-coding and collaborating with peers
- Attained structured, hands on experience coding for full stack development.
- Training on backend and front end technologies.
- Experience leading coding group.

**P&C Insurance License (#3402472):** Georgia Dept. of Insurance, Atlanta, GA 2021

**BA of Studio Art, Minor of Marketing:** Georgia Southern University, Statesboro, GA 2015 – 2018

**AS of General Studies:** Georgia Military College, Milledgeville, GA 2010 – 2013

**High School Diploma:** Baldwin High School, Milledgeville, GA

2006 - 2010